WASIF PERVAIZ

Dubai, United Arab Emirates Mobile No: +971544025071 wasifqureshi6@gmail.com Driving License: UAE Visa Status: Cancel

Professional Summary

Highly motivated individual with more than 5 years of experience in multinational companies. Proficient in hardware, networking and software. Solid track record of providing the timely positive response to requests regarding computer network-related assistance. A deep understanding of the general organizational confidentiality policies associated with IT specialist position.

CAREER SKILLS:

ITIL Certified Ticket/Incident Management System
Service Desk Analyst Excellent Skills in Managing Data Reports

Hardware Repairing & Troubleshooting
Operating System (Win 7, 8, 10)
Scripting
Customer Service
Problem-solving
System Engineering
Cloud Technology
Router, Switch
Creative Thinker
Asset Management
Networking & Security

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Creative Technology Solutions</u> (Dubai UAE) September 2018 – Dec 2019 (Company providing IT solutions for the International schools in the Middle East)

Information Technology Specialist

- Ability to provide 24/7 support
- Provides telephone, in-person, and online support to end-users and customers.
- Support the deployment, monitoring, maintenance, development, upgrade, and operation of IT equipment and software
- Install the servers, OS and administrate the related domains for the zone
- Maintain data centers and all servers of the zone.
- Oversee support to users in the areas of e-mail, directories, standard Windows desktop applications, and applications developed or deployed.
- Ensure high quality technical support and increase client satisfaction.
- Install, configure, test, and maintain hardware and software.
- Monitor help desk ticketing system and ensure timely resolution.
- Establish customer service standards and best practices.
- Provide timely and accurate service consistently.
- Manage IT Helpdesk, develop processes, SLAs and KPIs for continuous improvement.
- Prepare Window image as per school demand and deploy.
- Purchase of new software and hardware equipment within the estimated limit of budget
- Refers major hardware problems to service personnel for correction
- Assists in research and procurement of computer accessories and supplies
- Participate in incident management meetings
- Head for the core hardware and software section. Train technicians and give them information about new technology.

 Recommend process improvements to ensure system reliability, scalability, security, integrity and performance.

Geidea Solution (Saudi Arabia)

Sept 2015– Sept 2018

(Leading IT Solution company providing IT, Hotel Management and POS banking solution in the Middle East and India)

Information Technology Engineer

- Installed POS, mPOS, Cash Registers and Ticketing devices in the field and Supported POS software's, hardware development cycle to include needs analysis, specifications, testing, troubleshooting and deployment.
- Raised and follow up on Ticketing System to solve incident request according to SLA.
- Provides support to end users with technical problems and on a variety of issues.
- Monitor and triage incoming tickets in the IT Helpdesk Ticket Queue.
- Administrate user account and essential IT services such as email, file sharing, and collaboration tools.
- Informed customers on progress within agreed SLA timescales.
- Liaised with external clients and internal stakeholders to provide solutions and ensure service level agreements are met.

Sambo Engineering Co. LLD (Pakistan)

August 2014 – 2015

(Multinational company of construction)

Information Technology Officer

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems and networks.
- Responding in a timely manner to service issues and request.
- Providing technical support across the company (this may be in person or over the phone).
- Setting up accounts for new users.
- Repairing and replacing equipment as necessary.
- Testing new technology.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Science (B.S) Software Engineering Azad Jammu & Kashmir University Muzaffarabad Pakistan 2010 - 2014

CERTIFICATION

ITIL Certified (Axelos London)
MCSE Certified (Microsoft)

TRAINING

Microsoft (Teams, Azure, Intune) PMP (Project Management Institute)

LANGUAGE

English, Urdu, Arabic, Hindi